okay so continuing on with the saga of
好了，继续上的传奇
machine level programming when number
机器语言时数
four of our series of this and I think
我们这个 系列的四个，我 认为
that the total will be five so we're
该总量将有五个所以我们
almost through and as always this is a
几乎通过和 往常一样，这 是一个
lot of material for the course that's
很多材料的那课程
essentially a third of the course if you
本质上，如果你的课程第三
think about well no not that much but
想想还有没有没有那么多，但
it's a lot of the course and part that
它的很多 课程和一部分 的
we consider very central to it so a lot
我们认为非常核心的它，因此很多
of this involves since we're talking
这涉及到，因为我们正在 谈论
about a particular machine the Intel x86
有关特定机器的英特尔的x86
64 machines a lot of its kind of
64台机器有很多同类的
low-level nitty gritty stuff but part of
低层次的细节问题的东西，但部分
what we hope you also are understanding
我们希望你也理解
some of the general principles involved
所涉及 的一些基本原则
too and you'll find if you move from
过，如果你从移动，你会发现
this machine to another machine sort of
这台机器到另一台机器 排序
learning your first assembly languages
学习你的第一个汇编语言
your hardest one learning successive
你最难的一个 连续的学习
ones a lot easier so today we're going
那些轻松了很多所以今天我们要
to talk about data representations we've
谈论数据表示我们已经
so far all the programs we've looked at
到目前为止 ， 所有 我们已经看了节目
have been either just manipulating
已要么只是操纵
integers or long integers and pointers
整数或长整型和指针
so that's all what we'd call scalar data
所以这一切就是我们会打电话标量数据
data that's not in any aggregated form
数据是不以任何形式汇总
today we'll look at places where data
今天我们来看看地方数据
gets collected into you put together
被收集到你放在一起
multiple data elements and then see
多个数据 元素 ， 然后看到
there's really two ways to do that one
没什么两种方法可以做到这一个
is with arrays where you can create many
与数组，您可以创建许多
copies or many copies of an identical
副本或相同的许多拷贝
data types you can have an array of int
数据类型可以有一个 int 数组
and array of pointers a second is where
和指针阵列的第二种情况是
you have struck so you create a small
你打了，所以你创建一个小的
collection of values that can be of
值的集合， 可以是
different data types and each one you
不同的数据类型 和每一个你
access by its name or a tag and it turns
它的名字或标记 ，它原来的访问
out those definitions can be recursive
从这些定义可以是递归
so you can have arrays of structs and
所以你可以有结构的阵列和
structs with arrays and nested it to an
与阵列结构和它嵌套到一
arbitrary degree
任意度
and what we'll see is both how its
而我们将看到的是 两个怎样 的
represented in the machine memory and
在机器存储器表示，并且
also then what the code looks like that
还那么什么代码看起来 像
will manipulate these different data
将操纵这些不同的数据
structures and the main thing to see is
结构和看到的是主要的事情
that there's no the at the machine code
有没有对在机器 代码
level there is no notion of an array
水平没有 阵列的 概念
that you'd have at a high level except
那你就必须在不同的较高水平
to think of it as a collection of bytes
把它作为一个字节的集合
that you can are in contiguous part of
你可以在连续的一部分
storage and same with a struct is just
存储和同一个结构就是
allocated as a collection of bytes and
分配为字节的集合，
it's the job of the C compiler then to
它的 C编译器 的工作，然后到
generate the appropriate code to
生成相应的代码以
allocate that memory to get the right
分配内存以获得正确的
value when you refer to some element of
当你指的是有些元素值
a struct or in a read but the good news
一个结构或读，但好 消息
is this is such a commonplace type of
是这是这样一个 普遍型的
requirement for a programming language
为编程语言要求
that the Machine gives you sort of
该 机器可以让你排序
instructions that you'll see now they
你会看到，现在他们的指令
make perfect sense they're exactly
非常清楚了，他们说的完全
designed for this particular class of
专为这一特定类的
applications so we'll talk about
应用程序，因此我们将谈论
structure A's first and then structures
结构A的第一，然后结构
who struck and I'll also mention we'll
谁击中我也将提到我们
do a little bit I'll give you a glimpse
做一点点 我给你的 一瞥
of floating point today too because it's
浮点今天 也 因为它是
it's worth knowing how floating point
这是值得知道如何浮点
arithmetic is implemented as well on a
算法实现，以及在
machine so the basic idea of array
机所以阵列的基本思想
allocation is fairly straightforward if
分配是，如果相当简单
you have n an array with n elements then
您有n个具有n个元素的数组然后
that's represented by enough bytes in
多数民众赞成在足够的字节表示
memory all in one span to hold that much
内存都在一个跨度来保存多
data so if the underlying data type say
数据，以便如果基础 数据类型说
it's an int or a care is a single byte
它是一个int 或 保健 是一个单字节
of data type so to have a array of 12
数据的类型，以便为具有 12 的阵列
cares takes 12 bytes and int takes four
管它需要12个字节和INT需要四个
bytes so to have an array of five int
字节，因此以具有 五个 int 数组
take 20 bytes you get the idea you just
需要20个字节你的想法 ，你刚
multiply the size the underlying data
乘以大小 底层数据
type by the number of elements and
通过 元件 的数量 和类型
that's how big the array has to be in
这就是数组有多大是 在
terms of bytes
字节为单位
and we've already seen that in the care
我们已经看到 ， 在护理
is one bite and it is for a double or a
是一个咬合，它为双键或
long would be eight bytes and so would
长是八个字节，因此会
be a pointer so those are all different
是一个指针 ，以便那些都 不同
amounts of storage and you see in this
的存储空间，你在这看
diagram we use the X denote the starting
图中我们用X表示起点
address of the beginning of this region
该区域的开始地址
of memory and so we can use address
记忆，所以我们可以利用地址
computation to compute offset by adding
计算来计算，加入偏移
numbers to X to get the address in
号码X 得到 的地址
particulars of this array and that's
该阵列的细节，这就是
exactly what the code does so in general
正是代码一般做什么等等
then if you imagine array a has some
那么，如果你想象阵列有一些
underlying type T what the elements of
底层类型 T什么的元素
the array are and some number of
该阵列是和若干
elements in that array in the
在该数组中的元素
declaration L then we will that
声明大号 那么我们会说
declaration actually does two things
声明实际上做了两件事
one is it allocates enough bytes of
一个是它分配的足够的字节
storage to hold the entire array and the
存储保存整个 阵列与所述
second from a programming language
第二，从一种编程语言
perspective it is the identifier of the
透视它 的 识别符
array a can in some ways be treated like
阵列中的某些方面的罐等处理
a pointer that you can do pointer
一个指针， 你 可以做指针
arithmetic off of it and that's one of
它的算术关闭， 这是一
the features of C that is was a fairly
C的特点是 是一个相当
unique to see when it was created and is
唯一 看到它的创建 ，是 当
still unique to this day this idea of
仍然是独一无二的，这一天这个想法
the sort of interchangeability of
排序的互换性
pointers and arrays array identifiers so
指针和数组数组标识符，以便
for example I can use an array notation
例如我可以 使用数组符号
to say Val of four is element four of
说四瓦尔是元素4
this array and it's a five element array
这阵， 这是一个五元阵
so that would just be this final element
所以这将仅仅是这最后一个元素
but I can also just refer to Val and its
但我也可以只指瓦尔和其
underlying data type is as an int star
底层数据类型是作为int 星
so pointer to imp and its value would be
所以指针小鬼 ，其价值将是
X it's just a pointer a pointer is
X，它只是 一个指针的指针 是
remember an address and it's just the
记得一个地址，它只是
address at the beginning of the array
在 阵列 的起始地址
and I can do pointer arithmetic on Val
我可以做瓦尔指针运算
which as you know in
正如你知道的
II and this is a little confusing we'll
II，这是一个有点混乱，我们将
have to we'll go back and forth because
有我们来回走，因为
in C when you do pointer arithmetic like
用C当 你指针运算 像
you say you know P plus pause for a
你说你知道八方停顿了
pointer we just give you an example so
指针我们只是举一个例子 因此
if you had something like care star P as
如果你有这样的事情护理星数p作为
a declaration and you said P is equal to
声明和你说的P等于
some string s and then you say P plus
一些字符串s，然后你说八方
plus so you're incrementing that pointer
加上所以你增加该指针
one in this case you're incrementing it
一个在这种 情况下，你就递增
by one because the underlying data type
由之一，因为基础数据类型
is a is a care but if you said something
一个是照顾，但如果你说了些什么
like in star or caught IP and I
像明星或 捕获 IP和我
different pen
不同的笔
and I said you know IP plus plus then IP
我说你知道IP加再加然后IP
would get IP plus what does anyone know
将获得IP加什么没有人知道
for yes so it's a confusion and see this
（是）所以这是一个混乱和看到这
remember is the same as saying IP plus
记得 是一样的话说IP加
equals 1 but what you're actually doing
等于1，但你实际上在做什么
is incrementing that the number of the
被递增该的数
value of P by 4 because you want a
通过4 P的值，因为你要
pointer when you jump from one place to
指针，当你从一个 地方跳到
another you want it to increment by
另一个你想让 它通过递增
enough bytes to point to the next
足够的字节指向下一个
integer in this case for IP and so
整数在这种情况下，对于IP等
similarly valve s 1 denotes this value X
类似阀的 1表示该值X
plus 4 because it's a the address of the
再加上4，因为它是一个的地址
next integer in the array by the way the
顺便说阵列中的下一个整数的
one thing different between an array and
一件事的阵列之间不同
a pointer is I can't say Val plus plus
一个指针是我不能说瓦尔加上加
right I can't change the value of valid
好吧 ，我不能改变的 有效 价值
fixed by the declaration whereas a
固定由该声明 而
pointer I can increment it I can change
指针我可以增加它，我可以 改变
it in various ways and similarly
它以不同的 方式 和同样
ampersand L of 2 says give me the
2符号大号说给我
address of the second element of the
的 第二元件的地址
array so that would be at X plus 8 and
阵列所以这将 是在X 加上8和
this is again one of the fundamental
这又是根本的一个
properties of see that
的性质看到，
basically in NC if you take a pointer
基本上在NC，如果你把一个指针
that's rude
这是粗鲁
this is an eye not very well written
这是不是写得很好的眼睛
these are equivalent statement right
这些 是等价的说法对
there just two notations for the same
有 只有 两个符号 的相同
thing
事情
so on the upper part it says IP plus two
等上半部分它说，IP 加 二
meaning actually add 8 to I pee and then
实际上这意味着增加 8〜我撒尿，然后
dereference that it's the same as
解引用它的同
finding the second element of array an
发现阵列的的第二个元素
imaginary array of where IP is indicates
的其中IP 是假想数组指示
the beginning of the array so that's a
数组的开头，这样的一个
very fundamental principle of see that
看的 非常基本原则
again this whole idea of pointer
指针再次这一整体思路
arithmetic is fairly unique to see
算术是相当独特的，看
question yes
问题是
the compiler will happily let you use
编译器会很乐意让你使用
negative values for array indices and it
对数组的下标，它的负值
will give you a potentially undefined
会给你一个潜在的不确定
value but there's nothing in C that
价值，但没有什么用C是
prevents you from giving out of bounds
防止你界发放
either numbers that are too big for an
无论是数字，是太大的
array or too small for an array there's
阵列或太小的数组有
no bounds checking it yes if we have
没有边界检查， 这是如果我们有
some fun Megan and disaster
一些有趣的 梅根 和灾难
yes the question that's becoming what
对这个 问题这一点变得什么
about negative indices and the answer is
关于负指数和 答案
very simple because in other words in
因为在换句话说很简单
general something like IP plus X maybe
一般 像IP 加X也许
there can you see it
那里可以看到它
should I try to kind of break is really
我应该尝试一种突破是真的
equivalent to I T plus 4x
相当于IT加4倍
so this is the notation and until in our
所以这是符号，直到我们
derivative you and the right-hand side
导你和右侧
is the computation so you and see you
是计算的 ，所以你看你
write it using you don't have to give
使用你不必给它写
scaling factors to your data types
比例因子对你的数据类型
otherwise it would drive you out of your
否则会把你 出 你的
mind
心神
but you secretly underneath when the
但你偷偷下当
compiler generates the code we'll see
编译器生成我们将看到的代码
examples of this it's scaling everything
这方面的例子是缩放 一切
so now the question that is being asked
所以现在 被问 的 问题
is what if X is a negative number
是，如果X是什么负数
well the rule still applies it's just
以及规则仍然适用， 这只是
that the final result will be less than
最后的结果 将 小于
IP instead of greater than IP but it's
IP而不是比IP更高，但它的
totally valid C and there's actually
完全有效的 C，实际上有
times you will use it in this term I can
有时你会在这学期我可以用它
promise you yes question how do you know
答应你的问题是 你怎么知道
you can't write to plus IP try it
你不能写加IP试试吧
I'm pretty sure you can't do that in
我敢肯定你不能这样做，在
with pointer arithmetic try if somebody
指针算法尝试，如果有人
wants to type in some code and do it I
要搞键入一些代码，做我
don't think you can do that but if you
不要以为 你能做到这一点，但如果你
did it would have to figure it out that
没那就要 弄清楚 的是
you know the parser knows the datatypes
你知道解析器知道数据类型
of its two arguments so yeah you could
它的两个参数所以是你能
probably do it I've never seen this you
可能做到 这一点我从来没有 见过这个你
could do it but the compiler would know
能做到这一点，但是编译器会知道
that one of the arguments is a pointer
该的参数之一是一个指针
and therefore scale the other what you
因此，缩放等你
can't do is add two pointers you can
不能做的就是添加两个指针，你 可以
take the difference to two pointers this
走差异化，以两个指针这个
is obscure I'm not even going to tell
是模糊的，我也不打算告诉
you about this hook it up in knr but you
你这个把它挂在 KNR 但你
can do arithmetic but you can only for
可以做算术，但你只能 为
addition it can only be one pointer and
此外，它只能是 一个指针，
one and then the other has to be a
一个，然后另一个必须是一个
regular integer value and it will scale
定期整数值，它会扩展
it appropriately so I believe you can do
它适当地让我相信 你能做到
it it's just somebody will smack you on
它它只是有人将上揍你
the back of the hand if you actually
在手背上 ，如果你真的
write code enough but not the compiler
写代码不够好，但不是编译
so in particular you know you can if you
所以特别是你知道你可以的，如果你
go beyond the bounds of an array of this
超越了这样的一个数组的边界
you'll get whatever is beyond the bounds
你会得到什么是登天
of that array
该数组的
and it might be an invalid or it might
它可能是一个无效的 或者它可能
not even be a valid address and you get
甚至不是 一个有效的地址，你会得到
a segmentation fault but more typically
段故障 但更典型地
you'll get some whatever it happens to
你会得到一些随便多
be there and that's not so bad when you
在那里，这不是那么糟糕，当你
read it but you can also potentially
读它，但你也可以潜在地
write it as we saw before and corrupt
把它写在我们之前看到的腐败
data that's already in memory so here's
数据中已有的内存中，因此这里的
again the same statement I was making
再次相同的 语句我正在
before that IP valve plus I just get
该IP 阀前加我只是得到
scaled the value computed would be the
缩放计算将是的值
starting address plus four times
起始地址加 四倍
whatever eyes
无论眼睛
so let's look at so that's sort of
让我们看一下，这样的 排序
that's all see everything I said before
这是所有看到的一切我之前说的
is just basic see stuff now let's start
只是基本 看 的东西，现在让我们开始
looking at the actual machine code
看实际的机器 代码
involved and so I made up this example
参与等我提出了 这个例子
here where I declare three arrays each
在这儿，我宣布每三个数组
with five in and I go through what is
与五和我通过什么
considered sort of good form when you're
考虑排序的，当 你 的好形式
building up data that instead of having
建立数据 ，而不必
arbitrary constants sprinkled through
任意常数通过洒
your program often called magic numbers
你的程序通常被称为幻数
that you instead use a pound define and
您改用一斤定义和
you give it some meaningful name and
你给它一个有意义的名字和
some documentation usually at the top of
在顶部的一些文件，通常
a file or in a dot H file and then the
一个文件或 一个点.h文件，然后
type def is a very handy way if you're
类型定义是一个非常方便的方式，如果你是
going to create complex data structures
要创建复杂的数据结构
I highly recommend you sort of break
我强烈建议你排序突破
that into type deaths because the
到这类型的死亡， 因为
declaration notation in C gets fairly
在C声明符号变得相当
obscure fairly quickly but all this is
掩盖相当迅速，但是这一切都是
saying is the the data type I'm going to
俗话说是数据类型我要去
call a zip didge is defined to be five
调用一个zip didge被定义为五
an array of five int and now whenever I
5个int数组， 现在每当我
say zip did something I'm just popping
说拉链做了什么，我 只是突然出现
down I'm saying this is an array of five
下来我说这是五个数组
int and so I created three of them with
诠释，所以我创造了 他们 三人 用
the appropriate depth codes for the
为适当的深度码
schools represented here and now I'm
这里的学校代表，现在我
just making up for sake of presentation
只是弥补了演示着想
actual addresses for these in general
一般这些实际地址
you don't have any control over that and
你没有 过任何 的控制 和
I made it up so that they all happen to
我做起来 ， 使 它们都发生在
be in contiguous part of memory and
在连续的内存部分和
again there's no fundamental reason that
再没有根本的原因，
should be true so you can never trust
这样你就可以 永远不要相信应该是真实的
what particular address anything is ever
什么特定的地址什么是有史以来
going to be allocated at but you are
要在被分配但你
certain that each of these blocks will
肯定的是， 这些块的 每 将
be a contiguous collection of 20 bytes
是20个字节的连续集合
so here's some example code then to say
所以这里的一些示例代码，然后说
I want to retrieve for one of these
我想检索其中之一
arrays I want to retrieve a element
阵列我想检索元素
whose index is digit and this gets
其索引数字，这得到
turned into the following code so
变成下面的代码，以便
remember the first argument which will
还记得第一个参数这将
be a pointer now will be passed in
是指针现在将被传递
register RDI and the second will it will
寄存器RDI和第二将它会
be an INT will be passed and register
为 INT将被传递并注册
RSI and what I want to get out of this
RSI， 我想 离开这里什么
is an int and so you see that it here's
是一个int， 所以 你看 它这里的
where that scaled addressing this is
该缩放处理，这是其中
exactly what it was designed for and why
正是它的设计 以及为什么
why they went to the trouble of adding
为什么他们去加入的麻烦
the sort of fancy address modes to x86
那种花哨的地址模式的x86
because this is such a common thing so
因为这是这样一个共同的 东西 ，所以
remember what this says is take RDI
记住这说的是采取RDI
and add to it what you get by
并加入到它，你将得到什么
multiplying RSI by four so you scale
四，所以你的规模乘以RSI
that and of course that's exactly the
那当然这也 正是
computation we want to do if we compare
计算我们想如果我们比较做
it to you know what this is what we're
它给 你知道 这是什么 ，我们在做 什么
trying to get computed it's exactly it's
试图让计算它正是它的
exactly this computation here and that
这里正是这种计算和
gives us an address and then we're
为我们提供了一个地址，然后我们
reading from that address and we're
从该 地址读取和我们
going to copy it in EAX remember this is
将它复制EAX记住这是
an in total be in the e-version the
在一个总是在e-版本的
lower 4 bytes of register raf and that's
下4个字节寄存器RAF的，这就是
all the code it takes to implement this
所有的代码才能实现这个
particular operation yes RDI is the base
特定操作 是RDI是基
address all right yeah and I on the
地址与 没事 啊，我
right side
右边
yeah this is a typo thank you thanks for
是啊，这是一个错字谢谢谢谢
pointing it out I'll make a note of that
指点一下，我会记下那
right so this slide is incorrect and
右所以这张幻灯片是不正确的，
I'll fix it so this should be our di
我会解决它 所以这 应该是我们的二
plus for RSI right thanks for noting
加上RSI正确的感谢注意
that let me make it
这让我使它
okay and so now let's just look at a
还好所以现在 就让我们来看 一个
another distant code in particular what
特别另一个遥远的代码 是什么
if I wanted to go through one of these
如果我想 经历这些中的一个
arrays and for every element of the
阵列和对于的每个元素
array add one to it so increment every
阵列添加一个给它 如此每递增
single element by one well first of all
通过一个孔首先单个元件
you can see that we're setting up a loop
你可以看到， 我们正在建立一个循环
and it uses the jump to middle of
并且它采用跳到中间
business where the initial part is to
企业里最初的部分是
jump to the test and all the testing
跳转到测试，所有测试
involves were increasing our a X's for I
包括增加了我们对X对 我
here and we're incrementing it and
在这里，我们正在增加，并
comparing it at various places but um
在不同的地方 ，但比较庵 它
here's the the line of code that does
这里的代码，不会对行
all the real work again it's taking the
所有的实际工作再次它采取 的
ice element which is in our ax scaling
冰元素这是我们的斧头 缩放
by four adding it to the base of the
由四个它添加到的基
array and that gives us an address and
阵列，并且为我们提供了一个地址 ，
now remember you can have an an
现在还记得，你可以 有一个
arithmetic instruction where the second
算术指令，其中所述第二
operand the destination is a memory
操作数目的地是存储器
reference and what this actually
参考什么这实际上
requires is to first read the original
要求是先读取原来的
value from the memory do the addition
从内存值 做加法
and then store the result back in memory
然后将结果存储回内存
so this one instruction is exactly
所以这一个指令是完全
encrypt doing this plus plus operation
加密这样加上加操作
on this stored data in the array
对数组中的该存储的数据
oh by the way I should mention the whole
哦，对了，我应该提全
idea of pointer arithmetic and and si
指针运算和和Si的想法
was a si was really people who'd
是一个SI是真正的人，谁知道
programmed an assembly code for most of
编程的汇编代码的大部分
their lives thinking about how could I
他们的生活想着 我 怎么可能
make this look like a high-level
让这个看起来像一个 高层次的
language but keep all the flexibility
语言 ，但把所有的灵活性
all the tricks I learned to play at
所有的招数我学会在 玩
assembly code in a programming language
在编程语言汇编代码
because it was designed it was
因为它的设计 是
originally designed to implement an
最初设计到实施
operating system the UNIX operating
操作系统UNIX操作系统
system and historically operating
系统和历史操作
systems were written directly in
系统是在直接写
assembly code and these people Kernighan
汇编代码和这些人Kernighan的
Ritchie Dennis Ritchie and realized that
里奇丹尼斯·里奇，并意识到，
the way to do this is to sort of build
要做到这一点的方式是那种 建立
point arithmetic into a programming
浮点运算成编程
language so anyways the reason I'm
语言，所以反正 我 之所以 敢
saying this is you see a pretty close
说你看这是一个相当接近
correspondence here between instructions
对应此指令之间
and machine code and constructs in a
和机器代码和构建体 在一个
program in the C programming language
方案C编程语言
and that whole plus plus operator and
而全加加上运营商和
plus equals is sort of something you see
加等于就是那种你看到的东西
variations of institutes and we code ok
机构的变化和我们代码 确定
so that's a sort of single dimension
所以这是一种单一 维度 的
array and I'd like to just change things
阵列，我想 只是改变的事情
up a little bit by having a look at what
增长在 看看 有点 什么
the real difference is between of arrays
真正的区别是阵列之间
and pointers in a programming language
在编程语言指针
in C and so I have a couple of these
在C等我有一对夫妇的 这些
examples that I'll bring out one by one
我会 通过一个 带出 一个 实例
but the idea of this is you see the
但这个想法是你看
declaration on the Left there's
声明在左边 有
something called a1 and something called
一些所谓的A1和 被叫的东西
a 2 so call those a sub m and now what I
2 这样称呼那些子 米，现在 我 什么
want to know for each of these is does
想知道这些IS的呢
it compile is this a valid statement in
它编译这是一个 有效的声明
c ii with this potentially give me a
C II有这种可能给我一个
null pointer reference because i'm
空指针引用，因为我是
referencing a pointer
引用指针
for which the I haven't actually
对于其中我还没有 实际
allocated space for the that that
对于所分配的空间
pointer is indicated I haven't I haven't
指针指示我没有我没有
initialized the pointer to a valid
初始化指向有效
memory reference and then finally if I
内存参考，最后，如果我
were to use the sizeof operator on that
在其上使用的 sizeof操作符
particular value with that and including
与和包括特定值
for the case where there's a star in
对那里的以星形的情况下
front of it and a part of this is to
它的前面和 其中的一部分 是
understand the difference then between
理解上的差异则之间
an array and a pointer and the main
数组和一个指针和主
reason this the main factor is an array
原因， 这主要因素是一个数组
when you declare an array and see you're
当你声明一个数组，看看你
both you're actually allocating space
双方你实际分配空间
the space is being allocated somewhere
空间被 分配 的地方
for it and you're creating a using
对于它，你要创建一个使用
allowed to now use the Ray name of in
允许现在使用的雷名
pointer arithmetic whereas when you just
指针运算而当你刚
declare in a ret a pointer all you're
在退役声明指针所有你
allocating is the space for the pointer
分配是指针的空间
itself and not for anything that it's
本身，而不是任何东西，它的
you're pointing to so just - you've
你指着所以只是-你
probably figured out that these both
大概想通了 ，这些都
compile
编
let me get my chief chief Andy well but
让我得到我的首席首席安迪很好，但
what would be the size of a one here if
这将是 在这里如果一个一个的大小
I ran the size of operator on
我跑了运营商的规模上
let's do the easier one what's the size
让我们做一个更容易的什么大小
of a two eight because the pointer
一二八因为 指针
what's the size of a one a one is an
什么是一个大小的一个是一个
array of three in 12 right
在 12右侧 三 的阵列
oh and those those aren't no oops
噢，那这些都不是 没有哎呀
and now if I said star a one or start a
现在如果我说 一个 明星 或发起一个
- those would both compile could either
-那些既能编译既可以
of them possibly give you a null
他们可能的给你一个空
dereference oh yes the pointer itself is
提领哦，是指针本身是
no but that the I haven't dereferenced
没有但我已不会解除引用
it yet it's a null pointer but I haven't
这又是一个空指针，但我没有
it's not a bad potentially bad reference
这不是一个坏的潜在的不良参考
right it's not a runtime I will create a
右它不是一个 运行时我将创建一个
runtime error if I just say a - in my
运行时错误，如果我只是说了 -在我
code okay so your step ahead of me
码好了，所以我前面的你的脚步
basically so in it you kind of answered
所以基本上它你有种回答
the second question though this one
虽然这一个第二个问题
could give you a null pointer error if
可以给你一个空指针错误，如果
you try to dereference a pointer that
您尝试 取消引用 指针
hasn't been initialized it doesn't point
尚未初始化 它没有指向
to anything whereas this one is fine and
任何东西，而这一次是罚款和
now what's the size of a one of star a
现在什么是明星的一个的大小
1/4 and what about star a 2/4 yeah
1/4和大约明星2/4什么呀
because they're both pointers to ends so
因为他们都指向结束，因此
one way to think about that is as a
考虑这个问题的一种方式是作为
picture a one
图片一
is like we've been showing here it's an
就像我们一直在这里展示它是一个
array of of for intz and when I declare
的阵列， 用于intz 并且当我声明
a one I'm allocating all so the program
一个我分配所有这样的程序
is allocating 12 bytes of storage that's
被分配12个字节的存储空间这是的
able to hold that a 2 on the other hand
可以认为， 一个 2， 另一方面
is just a pointer which I'll show there
只是一个指针 ，我会告诉那里
until it's 8 bytes long but it doesn't
直到它的8个字节长，但它不
point to anything so that's what I meant
点什么，这样的 话是什么意思
that if you tried to say star a 2 you
如果你想 对我说星2 你
potentially have a null pointer
潜在地具有一个空指针
reference dereference out there and so
参考提领在那里等
that's why this is 8 and this is 12 so
这就是为什么这 是8，这是12这样
those are the warm-up 1 let's make it a
这些都是热身 1，让我们使它
little more interesting
更有趣
these aren't in the slides you'll notice
这些都不是在幻灯片中，你会发现
but I'm going to I'll update the slides
但我会我会更新的幻灯片
to include these later I'll but I think
后来包括这些我会，但我 认为
the point that if you find this
如果你觉得这点
confusing it's a sign that you really
混乱这是一个迹象，表明你真的
really really need to understand what a
真的 需要了解什么
pointer is and what an array is and how
指针是什么一个数组，以及如何
they're the same and how they're
它们是相同的，他们是如何
different because it's it's a it's a
不同的，因为这是它的一个它是一个
core part of programming and see that
规划的核心部分，并看到
will lead to endless hours of confusion
会导致混乱的无尽小时
if you don't really have this wired down
如果你真的没有这个有线下来
pretty strongly so let me just give you
相当强烈，所以让我给你
a preview of what's so interesting about
什么是如此有趣的一个预览
this is I'm going to give you some
这是我要给你一些
numbers and then we're going to have to
数字，然后我们将 不得不
explain how those numbers come around
解释这些数字是如何来到我身边
okay so let's try and understand what's
好了，所以让我们尝试和了解什么是
happening here and you see that all of
发生在这里，你会看到， 所有的
these declarations involve some
这些声明涉及一些
combination of pointer and array and the
指针和阵列和的组合
question is is it a pointer to an array
的问题是它是一个指向数组的指针
is it an array of pointers and the
是它的指针 和所述 的阵列
answer to those will depend on the
回答这些将取决于
particular syntax so of course the first
特定语法所以当然第一
one is one you've already seen before
一个 是一个你 以前 已经看过
and so you know that compiles and it's
所以你知道，编译和它的
not know and you can dereference it and
不知道， 你可以取消对它的引用和
it's not null but if you try to say star
它不为空，但如果你试着说 明星
star a one that's not valid it won't
星一 ，这不是 有效的它不会
even compile because you're trying to
甚至编译 ，因为你想
here take the data type of star a and is
这里需要明星的 数据类型 ，是
int and then you're trying to take a
诠释，然后你想 坐
dereference an int so that will compile
解引用一个int，以便将编译
and therefore you can't even test it
因此，你甚至不能进行测试
okay the question is for these other
还好 ，问题 是这些 其他
three you can see that somehow one is a
你们三个可以看到， 不知怎的 ， 一个是
well let's look at the bottom two first
那么让我们来看看在底部的两个第一
so the one on the bottom says that and
所以底部的一个说，和
this is part of and there's actually a
这是一部分，实际上是一个有
really great section in Kernighan
在 Kernighan的 真正 伟大的部分
Ritchie that I highly encourage you
里奇，我强烈建议你
which is how to read pointers how to
这是怎么 读指针如何
read declarations and see and the basic
阅读声明并看到和基本
rule is you start from the inside and
规则是你从内开始，
you work your way outward so that
你的工作你的 方式向外使
declaration of of a3 says that
的 A3 说， 声明
with that parentheses says a three is a
与括号说三是
what is victory
什么是 胜利
you
您
a three is a pointer that to parentheses
三是一个指针 ，以括号
around it
周围
what does it point to it points to an
这是什么指向它指向一个
array of three inch
三英寸阵列
okay so we can diagram a three then to
好了，所以我们可以关系图三再到
be something like this
是这样的
a three is a pointer like I said read it
三是一个指针，就像我所说的阅读
from the inside out
由内而外
a three as a pointer and what does it
三为指针，是什么
point to it points to an array of three
指向它指向3的阵列
elements and what type of elements are
元素和什么类型的元素是
they there in so you're sort of reading
他们在那里，所以 你要排序的阅读
outward and picking up pizzas from the
向外和拾取从比萨饼
right and from the left as you do this
右和左，你这样做
and so when you know that this all makes
所以，当你知道 ，这 一切都使
sense that these numbers the size of a3
某种意义上说 ， 这些 数字A3大小
itself is eight but since it points to
本身是八，但因为它指向
an array of three in the size of star a
三个星一个的尺寸的阵列
three is twelve and then star star a
三是十二点那么 明星明星
three would indicate this particular
其中3位表示这个特定的
element of the array and so it sizes
该阵列的元件，所以它尺寸
four so these all compile but which of
四个，这些都编译，但其中的
them could cause a null pointer
他们可能会导致空指针
dereferences which of the left two
解引用其中左边 两个
yes you can flip coin yes well I'm only
是的，你可以翻转硬币是很好，我只
looking at it I'm trying to fill in a
看着它我试图填写
three right now so a three is fine but
3，现在这样 三是不错，但
if I said star a three could that have a
如果我说明星三可能是有
null pointer of problem yes why because
问题空指针是为什么，因为
when I declare a three here all I'm
当我在这里宣布了三 所有我
declaring is this particular I'm only
声明是这个特殊的，我只是
allocating enough storage for that
分配为足够的存储空间
pointer I have an initial lot I haven't
指针我有一个 初步的很多我没有
allocated the space for an array I
分配的空间用于阵列我
haven't initialized a three to actually
没有初始化的三到实际
point to an array so it could be a null
指向的数组所以它 可能 是一个空
pointer it could be arbitrary junk but
指针时，它可以是任意的，但垃圾
it the chances of it actually pointing
它它的机会实际上是指向
to an array of three inches is highly
到三英寸 的阵列 是高度
unlikely so this would be a potentially
不可能因此这将是一个潜在的
bad and therefore double stars doubly
糟糕，因此双星双
dead right okay so now let's look at a
往右打死好了，现在让我们来看看一个
four so a four to understand that you
四个，四个明白，你
actually have to look at the charts and
其实有看走势图和
see the precedent chart which if you're
看看你是哪的先例图
like me your book falls open to that
像我这样你的书落在持开放 的态度
precedence chart the different operators
优先图表不同的运营商
and what levels they are and one thing
和他们是什么水平，一件事
you'll see is that a level one of
你会看到的是一个级别 的 一个
precedence the highest precedence
优先级最高的优先级
include square brackets and level to
包括方括号和水平
include star in other words bracket is
包括换句话说星托架是
higher precedence and star so this
更高的优先级和星级所以这
particular statement here
这里特别声明
the binding is is actually like this
绑定是实际上是这样的
it says that a four is an array of three
它说， 四为 三 的数组
elements and those elements are pointers
元素，并且这些元素是指针
and they point to in high so a four is
他们还指出，在 高 ，所以四是
an array can you see this but each of
一个数组，你可以看到这一点，但每个
those elements is pointing to an INT
这些元素是指向一个 INT
somewhere hopefully
希望某处
and so what the fat matches the numbers
还等什么脂肪的数量相匹配
we got so the size of a four is twenty
我们有这么四个大小二 十岁
four because it's eight times three
4周 ，因为它的八个时间的三个
if I were to dereference a four it would
如果我要提领的四它会
just indicate this particular pointer
只是表明这个特定的指针
right a four is an array of pointers so
右 四是一个指针数组 ，以便
when I get an element out of that array
当我得到一个元素的 是阵列的
what I'll get is a pointer and so of a
我会得到一个指针等的
four is a pointer and so it's also eight
四是一个指针，所以它也可以是八个
but if I now do a second dereference
但如果我现在做了第二次提领
then I'll get an int and it's size is
然后， 我会得到一个int和 它的大小是
four okay
4好吗
these all compile so could I have a it
这些所有的 编译，所以我可以有它
could start a for them of cause problems
可以开始他们的事业问题
as far as a null pointer or bed pointer
只要一个空指针或床上指针
no that's right no is the correct answer
没有这是正确的没有是正确答案
no is yes because you've a for this your
无是肯定的，因为你一本您
a for is an array you've you've defined
一对是你们一定数组已经定义
an array and it arrays get allocated by
数组并得到数组 分配由
their declaration as a for LM a three
他们作为一个LM的三个声明
element array on the other hand this
在另一方面 元件阵列 本
could give you a null pointer because I
可以给你一个空指针，因为我
haven't initialized the array to
没有初始化数组
anything so for example if it were
任何因此，例如，如果它是
initialized to all zeros it would just
初始化为全零 它只是
be three no null pointers in that array
是三个该阵列中没有空指针
so this is sort of that stuff the
所以这是有点那个东西
nitty-gritties of c question yes how
ç 问题 的一些本质gritties 是如何
does it know that the size twelve other
它知道 尺寸 其他 十二
side c didn't really know how many
正面c真的不知道多少
things are in an array the composite the
事情是在阵列中复合材料中的
question of how the compiler that what
如何编译器的问题是什么
i'm i'll into your question by saying
我是我会到你的问题说
remember the compiler knows a lot so the
记得 编译器知道 了很多，所以在
in particular I've declared this to be
特别是我已经声明这 是
an array of three pointers I'm compiling
的三分，我编译的数组
for a machine where pointers are eight
一台机器，其中三分球八
bytes and so the compiler knows that SP
字节，因此编译器 知道SP
24 bytes in general when you're when
24个字节一般，当你的时候
you're referencing and see there's no
如果引用， 看看有没有
you know the machine doesn't have built
你知道机器没有内置
into it any bounds and doesn't do bounds
到任何边界和不做界限
checking for you but that's in the
检查你 ，但是这是在
runtime execution if but in C if I when
运行时执行，如果但在 C，如果我当
I declare something it's known it has to
我宣布的东西它是已知它有
be known at that point when the
在这一点上是已知的，当
declaration occurs
声明 出现
question go back there so instead of
问题回到那里所以不是
doing three I just wanted empty bracket
做了 三 我只是 想空架
yeah I think empty bracket is is it just
是的，我认为闲置的支架是 它只是
another name for a pointer it's usually
另一名指针它通常是
it's just given as arguments some
它只是给出一些参数
restrictions on it but when you use the
它限制，但是当你使用
empty bracket notation and see it's
空括号标记，看看 它的
equivalent to doing a pointer
相当于做一个指针
declaration you're not allocating any
声明你没有分配任何
space for it one reality very different
它 一个现实 截然不同的空间
area yes right here it really means when
区域是 在这里 它的真正 含义时，
you declare an array and you give a
声明数组，你给一个
number the size of that array it really
确实许多阵列它的大小
allocates that memories if question yes
分配是回忆，如果问题是
oh yes and that's the final one you'll
哦，是的， 这就是 最后一个，你会
notice that the numbers for a 2 and a 4
注意到对于 a 2和a 4 中的数字
the same and the reason is it's the same
相同的， 原因是它的同
thing and that again goes by the
件事，再由去
precedence rules of see that a 2 first
优先规则看到， 第2
binds this way and then this way and so
结合这样的，那么这个方式等
a 2 and a 4 are synonymous just with
A 2和A 4都只是用同义
less parentheses
括号少
okay so that was a bit of an aside but
好了，所以这是 一个有点 题外话，但
as you can see I think this is the kind
你可以看到，我认为这是种
of thing that will really probe your
那 真的 会 探测你的 事
your understanding and now though it's a
你的理解， 现在虽然它是一个
beginning seed programmer where you
开始种子程序员，你
don't have a very good sense of the
没有一个很好 的 感觉
underlying representation of a program
程序的基本表示
it's really hard to figure these things
这真的很难想这些东西
out but now that you know what it means
了，但现在你知道这意味着什么
to compile code and you can actually
编译代码， 实际上 ，你可以
look at compiled code that'll sort of
看看编译代码，会有点
clear up a lot of the what's really
清理了很多 什么是真正的
going on in a program so let's now
在程序正在进行所以现在让我们
generalize from one dimension to two
概括从一名维两个
just to make life a little more
只是为了让生活多一点
interesting and again it's an important
有趣的 又一次 这是一个重要
principle to understand that in a one
原则上要明白，在一
you want to declare a multi-dimensional
要声明多维
array and see you do it by a sequence of
数组，看看你用的序列做
brackets with the balance for each one
与每一个平衡支架
and the reason for that is actually
而其中的原因 其实 是
there
那里
it will see that it has to do with this
它会看到它有这个做
notation that we just went through so if
符号，我们刚刚 通过 ，所以如果 去
I segment
I段
it turns out that I can read it like
事实证明，我可以读它像
this that a is an array of three
此a 是 3 的阵列
elements and each of those elements is
元素，其中每一 元素是
in itself an array of five elements of
本身五个元件的阵列
type int and we'll get back to that but
int类型，我们会回来这一点，但
that kind of explains everything I'm
那种解释一切我
about to tell you in this picture so in
要告诉 你 在这张照片 中如此
particular if I declare an array with
特别地，如果我声明与阵列
our rows and C columns and you think of
我们行C列，你想到的
it mathematically as sort of a matrix
它数学上 排序的矩阵的
two-dimensional matrix what it really
二维矩阵 它到底
does is it says look he is on the yep
所做的就是它说 看他是对 是的
sometimes see actually ends up being the
有时会看到实际上结束了作为
inner element it says first of all I
内部元件它说， 首先我的
want row 0 will be an array of C in
想行 0将 是 C的 阵列 中 的
being the number of columns
是列数
I'll put so all the elements of row 0
我会把0行 ，这样所有的元素
will come first all the elements of Row
会首先 行 的所有元素
1 come next and so forth up to the end
1来下并依此类推， 直到 结束
of it all and so the total allocation
这一切，并因此总分配
will be 4 times the data size times the
将4倍的数据大小倍
number of rows times the number of
的行数的次数
columns bytes but the reason why they're
列字节，但为什么他们的原因
in that order which is called row major
在被称为行主要是为了
order because if we thought of it these
为了因为如果我们认为它的这些
terms we go through the first row and
我们经历了第一排的条款和
then the second row in the third row is
然后 在第三行中的第二行是
precisely because of this
正是 因为 这一点
notation let me write it down like this
符号让我写 下来， 这样
int of a of well let me just use that
的井INT让我使用
the one I said you can write this out as
一个我说你可以这样写出来的
a is a array a free all may be right
一个是一个阵列 的自由所有可能是正确
over half and select 2/3
超过一半 并选择2/3
I'll just put it over here okay so a is
我只是把它在这里 好了， 一个是
the 3 element array and or generalizing
3元件阵列和或泛化
to this picture a is an array of our
这张 图a是一个数组我们
element this is the first element this
元件，这 是第 一个元素这
is the second element and this is the
为 第二元件，这是
arts element but what kind of elements
艺术元素，但什么样的元素
are those each is an array
是那些各自的阵列
of five minutes
五分钟
so within array a here each subpart of a
所以阵列内的位置的一个子部分的每个
then is an array of C in and so that's
然后是C的阵列中的和所以这是
why logically the way these are
为什么逻辑的方式 这些都
organized actually comes from this
其实组织源于此
declaration notation directly and what's
声明符号直接的，什么是
the examples of that so for example if I
的，这些实施例，以便， 例如，如果我
wanted to extend my zip tidge idea and
想延长我的 拉链tidge想法和
introduce an array of four of these I
介绍的这些 I 四个阵列
could declare it this way and again with
可以宣布它这种方式 ，再次用
remember I used a type def to declare
记得我用 一个类型DEF声明
zip tidge but if i were to expand this
拉链tidge但如果 我是扩大这个
out it was would be as if i was
出 它会像如果我是
declaring this array PGH to be a four
声明此数组PGH是一个四
rows and five columns but what it really
五列，但它真正的
is is the array of four elements one two
是在 四个 元件中的 一个 的 两个 阵列
three four each of which is an array of
三四 其中 的每 一个是阵列
five minutes okay so think of that
5分钟好了，所以想到的
nesting when you read declarations you
当你阅读声明你筑巢
start from the name of the element and
从元素 的名称开始，
you work your way outward through these
您完成这些工作的方式向外
brackets and stars in some order
支架和恒星以某种顺序
oh and so in particular if I want to
哦，所以特别是如果我想
reference a particular element of an
引用 的 特定元件
array
排列
the general rule is wrong here oh the
总的原则 是错在这里哦
general rule is this one if I want to
一般的规则是，如果我想这一个
reference literally
参考字面上
so I'm building up to it so yes this
所以我建立它，因此这是
shows that a of I I can actually just do
表明，第II实际上只是做
the reference a of I I don't have to
的II的参考不必
give a of I of J in C and what that
给出J的我在 C和什么
denotes is one of these our rows of the
表示这些是 我们 的行 之一
array and each of which is an array of
阵列和其各自是阵列
see elements of type int and so imagine
看到int类型的元素， 因此想象
that in general we have K bytes for data
在一般我们有 一个数据 k字节
type T the underlying data type in this
类型T在此基础数据类型
case of T is an int and K equals four
的T的情况下是一个int和K等于 四
but in general the starting address then
但在一般的起始地址，然后
of row I would be gotten by multiplying
行我会通过乘以得到
the number of columns by K and then
列由K和然后 数
multiplying that by the row number
乘以由行号
and now if within the array I want to
现在如果在阵列内我想
reference a ray element a sub IJ then it
引用 射线元件 的子IJ那么它
comes up to this computation you take
出现这种计算你拿
the starting address you scale the row
起始地址您缩放行
number by the number of columns add to
通过列数号码添加到
it which column you want and then
它的列你想，然后
multiply that all by okay so the way to
乘上所有好 了，顺便
see that is here I can get to row number
看到 这里 ，我可以得到行号
I by just scaling I by the number of
我通过刚才的数字缩放我
columns times the size of the elements
元件的列倍大小
are four and now I want to get to the JC
四，现在我想给JC
element of this sub array here and I can
这里该子排列元素，我可以
do that by scaling J by four and adding
做到这一点的四个缩放J 和添加
it to the beginning of this sub array
它 这个子数组的开头
and now I can just collect the force
现在我可以只 收集力
together and that's what and pull it
在一起，这就是将其拉
outside here that's what gives you this
这里之外，这就是给你这个
formula so again the the point of this
式，以便再次在的这一点
is that this all kind of is a natural
是， 这都挺是一种天然
outcome of the Declaration and it's easy
宣言 的结果 ，很容易
to think of it in terms of this storage
想起来在这个存储方面
model here of how the actual array is
模型的实际阵列是如何在这里
allocated
分配
okay now a different style of
现在没事了不同风格的
declaration is imagine I create three of
声明想象我创造三
these arrays and now I want to create an
这些阵列现在我想 创建一个
array that contains that appoints to
阵列包含任命到
these so this is a different data
这些所以这是一个不同的数据
structure you'll observe from before
结构，你会从之前观察
what Univ now is an array of three
什么 大学，现在是三个数组
pointers in each of those pointers
在每个 这些指针的指针
points to a one of these arrays of five
指向五个这些阵列的一个
ends
结束
you
您
and their underlying data type by the
以及由他们的基础数据类型
way of these elements are in stars right
这些元素的方式是正确的星星
and C does not differentiate when you
和C不区分 当你
want to declare a ring like this you
要声明环这样的你
just say it's an int star you don't say
只说这是一个int星你不说
how many elements are the underlying
有多少元素的底层
array is so you'll see by these picture
数组是这样，你会被 这些图片中 看到
that these are different data structures
这些是不同的数据结构
so now let's go through the what the
所以现在让我们通过 什么
assembly code looks like to reference
汇编代码看起来像到参考
these two data structures we didn't did
这两个数据结构，我们没有做
we do the I'm sorry I would have thought
我们 做了对不起我还 以为
I'd have assembly code system might be a
我不得不汇编代码系统可能是 一个
missing slide you so we'll see so
缺少幻灯片你，所以我们会看到这样
imagine I wanted to reference
想象一下，我想引用
I'm sorry I'm confused why there is no
我很抱歉， 我很困惑，为什么没有
ah
啊
they should have been I'm sorry this is
他们应该已经对不起，这是
uh
呃
I'm pausing here because I think I meant
因为我觉得我的意思是 ，我在这里暂停
to have a slide that would show what the
有一个幻灯片，将显示什么
code looks like and I don't
代码如下，我不
okay what we're going to have to wing it
还好我们将不得不临场发挥
so if you wanted to in assembly code
所以，如果你想在汇编 代码
then reference an element of an array
然后引用的阵列的元件
like this a multi-dimensional array what
像这样 的多维数组什么
you'll see is that the code kind of
你会看到的是，代码那种
builds up a computation like this and
建立了这样和计算
typically in the compiled code the value
通常在已编译的代码的值
of K is a kind of a constant value and
钾是一种恒定值 和
if it's a Ray that's been declared with
如果它是一个已经宣布了 雷
a constant bounds then the value of C
恒定的界限，则C的值
will also be a constant and so a piece
也将是一个常数，因此一块
of code for this and that's why got
对于这段代码，这就是为什么有
omitted by accident will basically take
偶然省略基本上 会 采取
this value and use some combination of
这个值和使用的某种组合
the memory referencing and shifting and
存储器引用和移位和
le.a instructions and so forth to
le.a指导等方式 来
implement this computation and then do a
实现这个计算，然后做一个
dereference so let's look at the second
取消引用所以让我们来看看第二
example and there is code for this and
例如并 有代码本和
it's actually a little bit more complex
它实际上是一个 更有点复杂
because this is going through two levels
因为这是经历两个级别
of indirection so you'll see that to get
间接的，所以你会看到，为了获得
the digit a particular digit from a
数字从一个特定的数字
particular of one of these universities
特别是，这些大学之一
then it has to first of all figure out
那么它必须首先弄清楚
do this D references get the a pointer
这样做三维引用获得一个指针
to the beginning of the array and that's
到数组的 开头 ，这就是
what this reference is doing here
这是什么参考这里做什么
okay but first of all what it's doing is
不错，但首先它在做什么是
shifting RSA I left by two which is
换档RSA余留由 两个其
equivalent to scaling the the digit by
等效于由缩放数字
four because it's getting ready to take
4，因为它准备 参加
that digit of parameter and scale it
参数的这一位 ，它的规模
appropriately and then it takes that
适当地 ，然后需要的是
number and add to it the value I get by
数量和添加到它我得到的价值
reading from their array Univ but using
从 他们的排列 读 大学，但使用
the index scaling it by eight to
该指数八缩放它
actually do a memory reference so
其实做一个内存引用这样
remember this instruction then and it
记住这个指令，然后它
looks a little weird is actually doing a
看起来有点怪异实际上是做了
memory reference here of this three
这里这三个内存引用
element array of called units so it's
称为单元的元件阵列所以它的
reading from memory and doing an array
从存储器中读出 和操作的方式的阵列
index directly here by scaling and now
指数直接在这里通过缩放和现在
getting from that a pointer adding to
从 一个指针增加越来越
that the the scaled value of of the
该的的经缩放的值
digit and so that gives me a pointer now
数字， 所以现在 给我 一个指针
as this notation shows to to the
因为这个符号表示向
particular element I want and now it
特定元素我想，现在
does a dereference so that's a pretty
做了这么解引用这是一个非常
tough example to get as you're one of
例如艰难获得尽可能你的一个
your first array one
你的第一个数组
and as I said I apologize for missing
正如我说我失踪道歉
the reference to a particular element of
提及的 特定元素
this array is done entirely by computing
这种阵列是通过计算完全完成
scaling indices in appropriate ways you
以适当的方式缩放你的索引
want to take the array and scale the
要采取的阵列和缩放
first index by 20 because each row is 20
第一索引20，因为每一行是20
elements it's 5 times 4 and you want to
元素是 5次4，你想
scale the digit by 4 to select the
由4 缩放 位选择
particular element within that array and
该 数组 内的特定元件 和
so you all this address computation
所以你这一切的地址计算
takes place and then there's a single
发生，然后有一个
memory reference whereas in this data
存储器参考而在此数据
structure you have to go through to
结构，必须要 经过
memory references first of all to you
首先是内存引用您
have to index and get the appropriate
有索引，并获得相应的
element here but that's just a pointer
这里元素，但是这只是一个指针
now and then we add an offset to that
现在，然后我们加一个偏移量是
pointer to get the appropriate element
指针，以获得适当的元素
in this array here and then we read from
此阵在这里，然后我们从阅读
that so that's what this notation means
这所以 这就是这个 符号表示
is that I'm doing two memory references
是， 我做 两个内存引用
here and just one there and it's a
在这里，只是一个人也没有，这是一个
little bit curious because if you look
有点好奇， 因为如果你看
in the C code it looks the same but the
在C代码看起来相同的 ，但
underlying data types are different and
底层数据的类型是不同的，并且
so the references are different
所以引用是不同的
okay so let's look at some other
好了，让我们来看看其他一些
variations on this code and these are
在此代码，并且这些变化是
all we'll do to fall out from these
所有我们要做 的， 从这些脱落
general principles I've described so
我这样描述的一般原则
first of all what introduced an array a
首先 ， 介绍了 什么 一个数组
two by two
两个两个
I'm sorry sixteen by sixteen array of
我十六个阵列对不起16
intz and it used to be and see if you
intz和它曾经是 ，看看你
wanted to do multi-dimensional arrays
想做多维数组
where the size of the array was not
其中阵列的尺寸不
fixed at compile time you basically had
固定在编译的时候，你基本上有
to implement your own version of that
要实现自己的这个版本
computation I showed before of scaling
计算我发现之前 的缩放
the the row number by the number of
通过数量的行号
columns and adding to it J so this is
列和增加它 Ĵ所以这是
sort of classic C I've written it as a
那种经典的C我写它作为一个
macro here but you can see it it's just
宏在这里，但你可以看到它，它只是
doing the row major scaling directly
直接做行大尺度
here is the address arithmetic now since
这里是地址运算，因为现在
a more recent generation of the C
更近的一代的C
compiler what they call c99 it was
编译他们所谓的C99是
introduced in 1999 you can actually pass
1999年推出实际上你可以 通过
as a parameter an array where the number
作为参数的阵列，其中所述数
of elements in the array is also a
数组中元素的也是
parameter that's being passed to the
多数民众赞成被传递到参数
function and similarly you can declare
功能，同样可以声明
an array to be of n elements as long as
阵列是 n个 元素 的 ，只要
n has been computed before it hits that
n所计算在击中前
array declaration and the compiler will
数组声明和编译器将
do the right thing it will allocate the
这样做将分配正确的事
proper number of elements
元素的适当数量
um so let's just look at some of this
嗯所以我们就来看看一些 这
code examples and again what we'll see
代码示例，并再次我们会看到
here and this will show you an example
在这里，这将 告诉 你一个例子
of the two turrets the the kind of
两个塔楼 的那种 的
address computation that takes place
地址计算，发生
with a two dimensional array in this
在 此 二维阵列
case I know C is 16 and K is 4 so if I
情况下， 我知道C是16，K是4，所以如果我
want to get element I sub j IJ out of
想获得元素i个子ĴIJ出来的
this array then first of all scale I by
这个数组然后通过首先规模 我的
64 because that's and I'll add that to
64，因为这是我将它添加到
the base and then I'll scale RDX by 4
基地，然后我就规模RDX 4
that's J and add it to this array and so
这就是J和它添加 到这个阵列 等
and then do a memory reference there so
然后做一个内存引用有这么
in the end I'm doing you see these two
到底我做你看这两个
instructions have done the appropriate
说明也做了相应的
the three instructions have done the
这 三个指令已完成
appropriate scaling of I and J as of
的I和J适当的缩放作为
them to the beginning address of a and
他们的起始地址和
I've done the computation on the other
我已经做了计算上的其他
hand if it's a 1 the third example I
另一方面，如果它是一个1个的第三个例子我
showed where N is a parameter that's
结果显示，其中N是一个参数， 这是
passed to the function so it's not known
传递给函数，所以它不是已知
at compile time
在编译时
how big a scaling factor to use you see
有多大比例因子使用 你看
that it has to use a multiply
它必须使用一个乘法
instruction to do that which is a
指令做这是一个
relatively expensive instruction in
在相对昂贵的指令
terms of performance and then once it
性能方面， 然后，一旦
has that that's just n times I and then
有这只是N次我再
it uses various combinations of le A's
它采用的勒 着的各种组合
and the scaling notation from before to
和缩放符号从之前
compute an appropriate offset into the
计算一个适当的偏移到
array to do the reference so here I
数组做参照，以便我在这里
could do it with a shift and here I had
可以用一个轮班做，在这里我有
to introduce a multiply because I don't
引进乘法，因为我不
know in advance how big it is if you
事先知道它到底有多大，如果你
want to torture yourself here's an
想折磨自己在这里是一个
example I was going to go over of triply
例如，我 是去的三重过
nested possibilities and dereferencing
嵌套的可能性和非关联化
of the same idea but let's move on to
同样的想法， 但让我们继续
pointers oh it just drugs so the idea of
三分球哦，它只是使药物的想法
a struct is actually quite simple oh
一个结构其实很简单哦
well the base idea is since when it gets
良好的基础理念 是因为它得到的时候
more complicated
更复杂
oh the idea that is I want to I declare
噢， 那是 想法 我想 我声明
a struct to have some number of fields
一个结构有领域的一些数
each of which can be an int or it could
其中的每一个可以是一个int，或者它可以
be in this case a pointer or it could be
在这种情况下，一个指针，也可能是
an array itself but the rule is
阵列本身，而是该规则是
basically what I'll do is allocate
基本上是我要做的就是分配
enough space if I introduce one of these
足够的空间，如果我介绍的这些中的一个
drugs for all the different array
药物对所有 不同的阵列
elements fields and that our struct and
要素领域和我们的结构和
then I'll I'll basically keep track the
然后 我会 ，我会 基本保持跟踪
compiler will keep track of where each
编译器会跟踪每个 的
of these fields starts and generate the
这些领域的开始，并生成
appropriate code to offset from the
适当的代码来从偏移
beginning so the structure itself the
所以开始的结构本身的
reference to it will be the beginning
提到这将 是 开始
address of the struct and then I'll use
该结构的地址， 然后我将 使用
appropriate offset to get to the
适当偏移去的
different field so here's an example of
不同的字段 ，因此这里有一个例子
some code imagine I
一些代码想象我
have a struct a pointer to one of these
有一个结构的指针 ，其中之一
structures and I have an index and what
结构和我有一个索引，哪些
I want to do is get to the that
我想要做的就是在那
appropriate part of array a within this
内此阵列的适当部分
struct well array a is right at the
结构以及阵列的是正确的
beginning of the structure so I can
结构 的开始 ，所以我可以
treat this just like I would any array
对待这就像我想任何数组
reference of scaling idx by 4 and adding
由 4缩放IDX 和添加的参考
it to the base to get the appropriate
它基本能得到 相应的
element so I don't really have to do
元素，所以我真的没有做
anything special
什么特别的
for this one let's go get some other
这一个让我们去得到一些其他的
code that you'll typically see actually
代码，您通常会真正看到
this example is pretty involved so I'm
这个例子是相当参与，所以我
actually doing a whole bunch of stuff
实际上做了一大堆 的东西
here with this one struct first of all
这里所有的这一个结构第一
I'm trying to retrieve element I from
我试图 从 检索元素 我
the structure then I'm using that to
结构然后我使用到
index into array a and and insert a
索引阵列的和，并插入一个
value into there and then I'm updating
值到那里，然后我更新
this pointer to point to the next
这个指针指向下一个
I'm if this were a link twist
我 如果这是一个 扭曲 链接
what I want to do is step to the next
我想要做的是一步到下一步
owner is a list so I need to retrieve
店主是一个列表，所以我需要找回
the next field from here and so these in
从这里 等等这些 在未来的领域
so I'm actually making three references
所以实际上 ，我拍三级引用
to this structure and this one rather
这种结构 ， 这一个相当
small function so let's try and figure
小功能，所以让我们尝试和数字
it all out so first of all I have to
这一切所以 首先我要
retrieve element I from it and here you
我从它这里找回元素你
see that we know that element I is that
看到我们知道元素 我是
offset 16 and so and here's where you
偏移16等，在这里就是你
see that displacement field being used
看到位移场使用
in the memory reference exactly for this
在存储器参考恰好为此
purpose I want to take R but add 16 to
目的我想利用[R但增加16
it to get a memory address that I can
它得到 一个内存 地址， 我可以
use for
用于
for I and it you see it actually uses
因为我和它，你看到它实际上 使用
move slq because I itself is an int but
移动SLQ因为 我本身就是一个 int，但
I'm going to use it as an array index in
我将 用它作为数组 索引
which case I have to scale it I have to
我有这种情况下，以它的规模我要
do address arithmetic using 8 byte
不要使用8个字节的地址运算
quantities so this actually retrieves
批量所以实际上检索
the 4 byte value and does a sign
4字节值和做了 标志
extension on it and now what I want to
扩展它，现在我 想做的
do is store at a Val at element I and so
做的是存储在瓦尔的元素我等
here you'll see that it's using our ax
在这里你会看到，它的使用 我们的斧头
is the value of just computed for I
是 仅仅计算了我的价值
scale linked by 4 and using the starting
规模由 4 连接 并使用起始
address of the R which happens to be the
将R的地址，其恰好是
starting address of a as well and doing
开始的地址，以及和做
a store so that's sort of an array
商店所以这是某种数组
operation there and then the next part
操作那里，然后下一部分
is I'm going to offset 24 which is the
是我要 弥补24这是
position of next read from that location
从该位置下一次读取的位置
and store that in our GI which is aa R
并存储 在 我们的 GI AA级 [R
so this is the operation argit's our
所以这是操作argit的我们
arrow next and then the loop is I'm
旁边的箭头，然后循环是我
testing until R is no so that's going on
试验，直到R是没有那么这回事
here so you see that those three
在这里，所以你看，这三个
references to destruct we're implemented
引用破坏我们正在实施
using three instructions here so it's a
使用三个指令这里，所以它是一个
very direct mapping between the the code
该代码之间有非常直接的映射
here and the x86 instructions and part
这里与x86指令和部分
of the x86 instructions because this
因为这个的x86指令
kind of stuff is so commonplace in
这种东西 是非常普遍
programs they kind of made the
节目他们那种所做的
instructions map very directly toward
说明很直接朝地图
these operations and now you should
这些操作， 现在你 应该
probably see why all the bells and
大概明白为什么所有的钟声和
whistles are there for these address
口哨 在那里为这些地址
references questions what if I was
引用的问题是什么，如果我是
what if I was three I'm sorry because
如果我是三我很抱歉，因为
they fucking name 300 a had a eyes three
他们他妈的名300 有一个眼睛调查
elements yes it will access
元素是它将访问
actually I think that's the typo Hayes
其实我觉得这是错字 海耶斯
supposed to be for visit with them so if
应该参观他们 因此，如果
I for it would access itself yeah and it
我因为它将访问本身是啊，它
would mess things up question this is a
会误事的问题，这 是一个
typo by the way it should be a 4 yes a
错字的方式应该是4级是一个
null pointer I know is a 0
空指针我知道是0
so that's sort of the easy version of
所以这就是那种 简单 版
structs now let's make them a little
现在结构让我们让他们一点点
harder one is for reasons that are a bit
困难之一是该 有点 原因
obscure the machine generally prefers
模糊机通常更
that if you have a data type and
如果你有一个数据类型和
underlying data type of K bytes that the
的K基础数据类型字节 ，所述
address that that starts at be a
解决始于是
multiple of K and so that introduces a
的K多，并且使得引入了一个
property we call alignment which will
属性我们称之为对准这将
actually when a structure gets allocated
实际上，当一个 结构被分配
well the the compiler will actually
以及该 编译器将实际
insert some blank unused bytes in the
中插入一些空白未使用的字节
data structure in its allocation just so
在分配 数据 结构只是让
that it can maintain this alignment so
它可以保持调，以便
for example here I is a as an int and I
例如这里我是作为一个int 和我
want it to address to be a multiple of
希望它解决是的倍数
four now I'll give you a minute why
四岁了，我给你 一分钟 为什么
that's true
确实如此
I'll just so trust me for a minute and
我就这么信任我一分钟 ，
so it'll actually had three unused bytes
所以它会 实际上有三个字节
here because the first byte is being
这里，是因为第一个字节是被
used by C and in general we'll see in
使用C和一般我们会看到
the allocation we're going to make sure
我们要确保分配
that the pointer to this data structure
指针到该数据结构
is itself a multiple of eight and the
本身是 八和 多
reason for that is because there's a
原因是 因为有一个
double here and it should reside on a
这里的两倍，它应该驻留在
boundary that its starting address
边界， 它的起始地址
should be a multiple of eight and you
应该是 八 和你 多
see as long as this is eight a multiple
看到只要这是 八的倍数
of 8 and this offset here is a multiple
8，在这里这个偏移量是多
of 8 then this address will be a
的8则此地址将 是一个
multiple of eight so that's the idea of
八个多 所以这是 的想法
alignment and so why is that true well
对齐和为什么是真的 好
it's really a hardware issue that the
这真是一个硬件问题了
memory system instead of the actual
存储系统，而不是实际
hardware memory does not reference one
硬件存储器不引用 一个
byte at a time at references actually in
在以引用的时间其实字节
most machines nowadays about 64 bytes at
大多数机器目前约在64个字节
a time or depending on various widths
一个时间或 取决于各种宽度
within the hardware and in general if if
在硬件中和一般如果要是
a particular piece of data across is the
数据的 特定部分 横跨 是
boundaries between 2 blocks of that are
的 该 2块之间的边界
the
该
a misaligned address that will take
这将需要未对齐的地址
extra steps by the hardware and
由硬件额外的步骤 和
potentially even the operating system to
甚至可能操作系统
deal with so just for efficiency reason
对付这样只是为了效率的原因
they say do this alignment trust me in
他们说，这样做比对信任我
x86 machines if you have unaligned data
x86 上 ，如果您有未对齐数据
it will execute just fine it just might
它会执行得很好，它只是可能
run a little bit more slowly on some
在某些运行一点点更 慢
other machines if you try to do an
如果你尝试做的其他机器
unwind access it will actually cause a
放松访问它实际上会造成
memory fault question yes the cecum the
内存故障问题是 盲肠
question was how could you force it to
问题是， 你怎么可能强制
generate unwind data I don't know if you
产生展开数据 我不知道，如果你
could and we'll talk about ways you can
能和我们谈谈方法 可以
sort of be more clever in how you do
排序的是你怎么做更聪明
your allocation to avoid wasting space
你的配置，以避免浪费空间
so in general then we have we're mostly
所以一般那么 我们有我们大多
looking here at data types that are
看这里是数据类型
either 1 2 or 4 8 bytes long there are
是1个 或 2 4 8字节长有
some 16 byte data types but we won't be
一些16字节的数据类型，但我们不会
looking at those and in general would be
看着那些 和一般会
address then you can tell the alignment
地址，然后你可以告诉对齐
of an address by how many zeros if it's
由多少 个零的地址 ，如果是
a power of 2 alignment how many zeros
2对齐的功率有多少 个零
are at the end of a bit level
是在比特级别的端部
representation of that address and so as
该地址等作为表示
we showed in general the C compiler when
我们发现在一般的C 编译器时
it's creating the layout for a structure
它创造了一个结构布局
a struct will put in padding bytes in
一个结构 将投入 填充字节
there to make the alignment work the
有使对准工作
other thing it will do is if it need be
其他的事情会做的是，如果需要的话
it will add bytes to the end to make
这将增加 字节到底做
sure that the overall size of the data
确保数据的整体大小
structure meets whatever underlying
结构满足任何潜在的
alignment requirement there is and this
对齐要求有这
one because it contains a double the
之一，因为它包含一个双
overall data structure has to be aligned
总体数据结构具有对齐
on an 8 byte boundary
在8字节边界
and the reasoning for that is imagine I
和该推理 想象我
had an array of structs of these trucks
有这些卡车的 结构的数组
in particular then if I can assume that
尤其是那么如果我可以假设，
if I can ensure that this array is a
如果我能保证这个阵列是一个
multi address to the multiple of eight
多地址的 八个 多
then you can see that each successive
然后你可以看到，每个连续
element of this array of these trucks is
这个数组这些卡车的的元件是
a multiple of eight and then within that
八，然后多内
struct I've ensured that each field that
结构我保证每个字段
requires an alignment by eight is
需要八个的对准 是
positioned with an offset that's the
定位偏移是这样的
multiple of eight and so it all works
八个多，所以它的所有作品
out but if you try to tinker with this
了，但如果你试图 用 这个 鼓捣
by making this too short then you start
通过使该过短，那么你开始
getting misaligned reference
越来越错位参考
and so one thing you'll see is for every
而这么一件事，你将看到的是，每
struck the actual alignment requirement
袭击实际对齐要求
depends on what's the sort of worst-case
取决于什么是那种最坏情况
alignment the the maximum alignment of
对准的最大对齐
any element so this particular structure
因此这种特殊的结构的任何元件
for example contains a a float V which
例如含有氨基酸浮子 v哪种
has a size of four and so this would be
有四个大小，因此这将 是
an alignment of four and you'll see in
四个对齐，你会看到
the code in general when it has to this
一般的代码 时， 它有这个
all this address arithmetic we've seen
所有我们已经看到了这个地址运算
get fused in various different ways to
得到融合各种不同的方式来
scale values compute offsets and so
刻度值计算偏移等
forth to get the appropriate elements so
第四，以获得 相应的元素，因此
your question before is could I tell the
你的问题之前，也是我可以告诉
compiler not to do alignment and the
编译器不能做比对和
better way is to declare your fields in
更好的办法是宣布你的字段
a way that minimizes the amount of
最小化的量的方法
wasted space so for example here I
浪费的空间，所以 在这里我举例
wasted three bytes here and three bytes
浪费了三个字节在这里和三个字节
here to meet the alignment requirements
在这里，以满足对齐要求
but if I just put I at the beginning and
但如果我 只是把我在开始和
then C and D I would have only wasted
那么C和DI会不仅浪费
two bytes total and in general because
两个字节总数和一般，因为
all the alignment requirements are
所有的走线要求
powers of two the sort of greedy
两个的那种 贪婪的权力
algorithm works it says if I just take
算法的工作，它说如果我只拿
put the biggest stuff at the beginning
把最大的东西在开始
and then successfully smaller elements I
然后 顺利较小的元素 我
will be able to minimize any wasted
将能够最大限度 地 减少浪费任何
space and that's a general property but
空间， 这是一个普遍特性，但
this is a case where you is the writer
这是你 是作家 的情况下，
of C code have that effect if the
的C代码 有，如果该效果
compiler will not do this for you
编译器不会 为 你 做这
automatically question oh Jesus well
自动质疑 哦耶稣以及
coming in
进来
under race what's that oh but remember
在比赛那是什么 哦，但是要记住
an array I don't care about the array I
数组我不关心我阵
care about the elements of the array
关心的阵列的元件
because this is only down at the lowest
因为这是唯一下降的最低的
level where I'm accessing either a
水平，我访问无论是
single int a single double or a pointer
单个int 单个双键或一个指针
and not all the rest of the stuff
而不是所有的东西休息
remember I never read an entire array
记得我 从来不看整个数组
from memory so alignment only refers
从存储器中 ，以便 对准仅指
down to the most the primitive types not
下到最原始类型不
the aggregate types if this is confusing
聚集类型，如果这是令人困惑
the book covers this fairly carefully so
这本书 相当仔细地 覆盖该 如此
let me just finish up with a little
让我只是完成了 一点点
glimpse of floating-point floating-point
浮点浮点一瞥
is a complicated history in x86 how back
在86 怎么回 一个复杂的历史
in the really ancient days
在真远古时代
there was a chip that went with the 8086
还有， 与8086走 了芯片
processor called the 8087 and at the
处理器称为8087，并在
time it was a masterpiece of engineering
一次是工程 的杰作
to be able to come all the hardware
要能够走到所有的硬件
necessary to implement full I Triple E
要落实全我三è
floating point on a single chip and it
浮点单个芯片和它上
was the first one of its type in fact it
是它 实际上 类型的第一个 它
was a sort of co-developed with the I
是一种与我共同开发
Triple E floating point standard itself
三重É浮点标准本身
but the programming model for it is
但它的编程模型
horrendously awful and ugly I used to an
可怕的窘况和丑陋的我用的
older addition to the book there were it
旧的除了书有它
was in the first edition it was in a
在第一版是在
website in the second edition and now
网站的 第二版 ，现在
it's been expunged completely because
它被完全抹去因
it's so awful but more recently in the
它最近是如此可怕，但在
world of x86 they realized that to
86的世界里，他们认识到，
support things like video and all the
支持诸如视频和所有的
stuff people actually do with their
东西的人其实与他们的
machines they needed some more
机器，他们需要更多一些
horsepower in numeric processing and
马力在数字处理 和
they implemented a class of instructions
他们实施了类指令
called SSE which stands for sim D
叫SSE它代表SIMð
something Cindy execution anyways and
辛迪的东西反正执行和
I'll show you in a minute what that
我会告诉你 在一 分钟内什么
means and that's now in the more recent
手段和现在的 更近
versions of x86 has been juiced up to
86版本已经榨汁达
something called a VX which but the
一种叫做VX这可是
shark machines support this version of
鲨鱼机支持这个版本的
what's called SSE so let me just give
什么叫SSE，所以让我只给
you a feeling for that and in
你对于 和 感觉
particularly the shark machine support
特别是鲨鱼机支持
what's called SSE version 3 and what it
什么叫SSE 3版以及它
is is that there are 16 special
是的是 ， 有 16个特殊
registers distinct from the other
记录来自其它不同
registers we've talked about before each
我们每个人以前讲过寄存器
of which has 16 bytes and then there's
其中有16个字节，然后有
operations that can operate on those and
可以对那些操作的操作和
treat them in different ways so one is
对待他们以不同的方式，使一个是
to treat this section of register as an
治疗寄存器的这一部分作为
array of sixteen cares or as eight of
的16只关心阵列或八个
shorts or four is or and also to support
短裤或四个是或并且还支持
a double floating-point arithmetic so
双浮点运算等等
this stuff was certainly going on and
这东西肯定是怎么回事，并
somebody had the observation that said
有人曾认为观察
well I could just then sort of subset
还有我可以再排序 的子集
all this and implement the
这一切和实施
floating-point operations directly using
直接使用浮点运算
this SSE stuff and skip the old x87
这SSE东西，并跳过旧的x87
stuff and so that's the way floating
的东西，所以这是 浮动 的方式
point is now generated on say the shark
现在上说， 鲨鱼 产生点
machines and most recent machines this
机器和最近该机器
is a this is again an example of where
是这个 被再次 的其中 一个 例子
the world is more complicated than it
世界是比它 更复杂
should have to be so for example there
应该有例如如此有
is an instruction that says add SS so
是说增加SS这样的指令
add a single scalar is what that
添加一个标是什么
notation add a single precision scalar
符号添加一个单精度标
at a scaler single-precision and it
在缩放器单精度和它
looks a little like the add instruction
看上去有点像add指令
the add Q instructions you've seen that
你已经看到了加Q指令
it it increments it adds the source to
它它增加它添加源
the destination there's ways I can do
目标 有方法 ，我可以做
for ads in a all at the same time using
使用 在同一 时间 在所有广告
this is what they call Cindy execution
这就是他们所谓的辛迪执行
which stands for single instruction
它代表单指令
multiple data one instruction the add
多个数据中的一个指令加载
PSP since repect
PSP自repect
will do will will perform that one
会做 的意愿将执行 一个
instruction will do ad with four
指令会做的广告有四个
different numbers and similar you can do
不同数量 和类似，你可以 做
it with double precision you can do one
它与双精度，你可以 做一个
of them you can do pet and so actually
他们可以做宠物 等 实际
the underlying and we'll see this when
底层 ， 我们将看到这个 时
we look at code optimizations if you
我们看一下代码优化，如果你
write codes to make use of these
写代码才能利用这些
instructions you can really boost the
说明你 才能 真正提振
performance of the computer but this
计算机的性能，但这种
just gives you a flavor for what
只是给你一个什么样的味道
floating-point code looks like and the
浮点代码看起来像和
rules are pretty simple that just as we
规则很简单，正如我们
saw before that that arguments get
看到之前那个论点得到
passed in in registers while 14-point
在寄存器中传递而在14点
arguments get passed in these xmm
论点得到这些XMM传递
registers x mmm 0 you don't have to
寄存器 X嗯0您不必
memorize our dir si RDX
记住我们的目录SI RDX
there in X mmm 0 1 2 it's all very
在X MMM有0 1 2这一切都非常
logical and the return value is in X mmm
逻辑和返回 值 是在 X MMM
0 and all the registers are calling
0和所有的寄存器被 调用
callers safe there's no calling safe so
来电者的安全有没有打电话的安全 ，这样
something like adding 2 floating point
像添加2 浮点
numbers will just look like a single
数字将只是看起来像一个单一的
floating point addition instruction same
浮点加法指令相同
with double and if you mix together code
双如果你混合在一起 码
that has a pointer and a floating point
具有一个指针和一个浮点
operator the pointer will be passed in a
操作指针 会在传递
regular register RDI and this double
定期寄存器RDI 和这双
will be passed in x mm 0 so it sort of
将因此它排序 X毫米0被传递
as it goes through the argument list you
因为它不用通过参数列表，你
sort of in the particular order if it's
那种在特定的顺序，如果是
an integer or a pointer it's in one of
的整数或者指针它在一个
the our registers and if it's a floating
在我们的寄存器，如果它是浮动
point value it's
点值 是
one of the xmm registers and potentially
的XMM寄存器中的一个的和潜在
interleaved
交错
almost done and so this is a code that
几乎完成，所以这是一个代码 ，
does this particular operation and it's
执行此特定的 操作，它的
interesting because it's returning a
有趣的，因为它 返回了
it's doing memory referencing so again
它做的内存，以便再次引用
there's instructions that will read from
还有，将读取指令
memory and copy into an XML register you
内存和复制到 一个XML您注册
can add registers you can make a copy of
可以添加寄存器 可以使副本
from one XML M register to another and
从一个XML M寄存器到另一个
you can store results so this code looks
你可以存储结果， 所以这段代码看起来
a lot like what you do in integer
很像 你 在整数 做 什么
arithmetic except it's using XML and
除了它的运算是一个使用XML和
special floating-point instructions
特殊的浮点指令
rather than the ones you've seen before
而不是你 以前 见过的那些
so the basic idea of it is fairly simple
所以 它的 基本思想 是相当简单
it gets way more complicated because
它获取的方式更加复杂，因为
there are lots of instructions double
有很多的双重指示
float on and on and on there's a special
漂浮在和和有特殊
instruction to do square root and all
指令做平方根和所有
this stuff and the comparison stuff is
这个东西和比较的东西
really nasty and messy and hard to
真是可恶和杂乱， 很难
understand and then you'll see various
了解，然后你会看到各种
tricks to use constant values to so it's
招数用常数值所以它的
covered in the book we're not going to
覆盖我们不打算书
really talk about it much in in this
真正谈论 它更 在此
course but the underlying the the basic
当然，但潜在的基本
principles of it are fairly
它的原理是相当
straightforward ok that'll do us for
简单的确定这会尽我们
today
今天